A Guide to the Henry Luce Foundation records, Record Group 6, Accession 2017:070 FA1523
Rockefeller Archive Center
Henry Luce Foundation records, Record Group 6, Accession 2017:070
1982-2013
Rockefeller Archive Center
Henry Luce Foundation
FA1523
31.68 Cubic Feet 72 letter-sized document boxes
Biographical / Historical
The Henry Luce Foundation was established by Henry R. Luce in 1936. As a New York-based nonprofit organization, the Luce Foundation awards grants in American Art, Asian studies, Higher Education, Theology, and supports the Clare Boothe Luce Program for women in science, mathematics, and engineering.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by the Henry Luce Foundation in 2017.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
When requesting to view audiovisual material, please refer to the Title and the AV Number (example: AV 1916). Researchers are asked to check the "Restrictions" note for each Title. If a Title does not currently have an access copy, please contact a RAC archivist for further instruction.
All inquiries to view films require advanced notice of at least 2 business days, and may necessitate notice of up to one week. Individual items, including those that are not available in modern formats, may be restricted from access at the discretion of RAC.
Scope and Contents
The Henry Luce Foundation records (Record Group 6) contains grant files.
Arrangement
The Henry Luce Foundation records (Record Group 6) are arranged as follows:
Series 1: Project Files, 1982-2013
Art, American; Research grants -- Asia, Southeastern; Education, Higher; Theology -- Scholarships, fellowships, etc.; United States -- Relations -- China
- Project Files, 1982-2013; 1
  - Aid to Artisans, Inc. - Arts Education and Exchange Project in Laos, 2004-2007 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Albany Institute of History and Art - Permanent Collection Exhibition Program (American Collections Enhancement (ACE) Initiative), 2000-2003 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Allentown Art Museum - Research and Conservation of "Return of the Prodigal Son" by Benjamin West, 2005-2007 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - America Abroad Media - Public Radio Programming on Religion and International Affairs (Renewal), 2010-2011 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - American Assembly - Religion Assembly of the Uniting America Series, 1999-2007 (Box 1, Folder 5-6)
  - American Council for Capital Formation - CAPTAX Initiative, 2003-2004 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - American Council for an Energy Efficient Economy - Appliance Efficiency Standards Research, 2000-2006 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - American Council of Learned Societies - Dissertation Programs in American Art, 1997-2000 (Box 2, Folder 9-12)
  - American Council of Learned Societies - Luce/ACLS Dissertation Fellowship Program in American Art (Renewal), 2000-2007 (Box 2, Box 13-14, Box 3, Folder 15-16)
  - American Institute of Physics - International Survey of Women in Physics, 2008-2013 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - American Society of Missiology - History of Christianity in Asia, 2003-2005 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Americans for the Arts - National Public Opinion Arts Survey, 2005-2006 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Amon Carter Museum of American Art - Curatorial Research Assistants (American Art Renewal Fund (AARF)), 2011-2013 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Andover Newton Theological School - Theology and the Arts Program, 1998-2001 (Box 4, Folder 21-22)
  - Archives of American Art - Guide to Diaries and the Jervis McEntee Diaries, 2003-2009 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Archives of American Art - "Philadelphia: A Guide to Art-Related Archival Materials", 1992-1994 (Box 69, Folder 440)
  - Arizona State University Foundation - Religion and International Affairs: Through the Prism of Rights and Gender, 2010-2013 (Box 4, Folder 24-25)
  - Art Institute of Chicago - American Art Catalog, 1999 (Box 69, Folder 441)
  - Art Institute of Chicago - "Taoism and the Arts of China" Exhibition and Catalog, 1999-2004 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Asia Foundation - Vietnam Exchange Program, 1999-2006 (Box 5, Folder 27-29)
  - Asia Society - "Monks and Merchants: Silk Roads Treasures from Northwest China" Exhibition and Catalog, 2000-2004 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Asian Cultural Council - American Artists and Museum Professionals in Asia, 2007-2011 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Asian Institute of Management - Fundraising Campaign, 2001-2002 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Associated Colleges of the South - Chinese Studies Initiative, 2007-2012 (Box 6, Folder 33-35)
  - Association of Theological Schools - Henry Luce III Fellows in Theology, 1996-2005 (Box 7, Folder 36-39)
  - Aspen Institute - Congressional Program on China (Renewal), 2000-2007 (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - Atlantic Council of the United States - Senior Fellows Program, 1996-2002 (Box 7, Folder 41)
  - Aquinas Institute of Theology - Integrate Lay Ministers into Parish Life, 1999-2003 (Box 8, Folder 42)
  - Baylor University - The Church and the Social Work Profession, 1999-2005 (Box 8, Folder 43-44)
  - Birmingham Museum of Art - 50th Anniversary Campaign to Promote the American Art Collection (American Collections Enhancement (ACE) Initiative), 2000-2003 (Box 8, Folder 45)
  - Jack S. Blanton Museum of Art, University of Texas at Austin - American Art Collection Catalog and Reinstallation, 2003-2007 (Box 8, Folder 46)
  - Boston University - Nonferrous Metallurgy Volume for the Science and Civilisation in China, 2003-2013 (Box 9, Folder 47-48)
  - Boston University - The Role of Religion in World Affairs, 2005-2013 (Box 9, Folder 49)
  - Boston University - Scripture and the Literary Arts, 1998-2006 (Box 9, Folder 50-52)
  - Bowdoin College - Merrymeeting Bay Long Term Ecological Research, 2003-2006 (Box 10, Folder 53-54)
  - Bowdoin College Museum of Art - Research Project and Lecture Series on the American Art Collection, 1996-2005 (Box 10, Folder 55)
  - Brandywine River Museum - Part-time Assistant Librarian, Assistant Curator, and Cost of Living Raises (American Art Renewal Fund), 2011-2013 (Box 10, Folder 56)
  - Bridge to Asia Foundation - Targeted Book Initiative for China, 2003-2006 (Box 10, Folder 57)
  - Brigham Young University Museum of Art - "The Weir Family, 1820-1920: Expanding the Traditions of American Art" Exhibition and Catalog, 2009-2013 (Box 11, Folder 58)
  - Brookings Institution - Center for Northeast Asian Policy Studies, 2001-2006 (Box 11, Folder 59)
  - Brooklyn Historical Society - American Paintings Conservation, 2012-2013 (Box 11, Folder 60)
  - Brooklyn Museum - "Youth and Beauty: Art of the American Twenties" Exhibition and Catalog, 2009-2013 (Box 11, Folder 61)
  - Brooks School - Capital Campaign, 2005-2006 (Box 11, Folder 62)
  - Brown University - Charles C. Tillinghast, Jr. '32 Professorship in International Studies, 1997-2005 (Box 11, Folder 63)
  - Buffalo Bill Historical Center - Digitized Photography of the Plains Indian Collection (American Collections Enhancement (ACE) Initiative), 2000-2005 (Box 11, Folder 64-65)
  - Buffalo Bill Historical Center - "William Ranney: An American Artist" Exhibition and Catalog, 2003-2007 (Box 12, Folder 66-67)
  - Butler Institute of American Art - Collections Management System, 2002-2006 (Box 12, Folder 68-69)
  - Carleton College - Integrative Spatial Modeling Project, 2007-2013 (Box 12, Folder 70-72)
  - Carnegie Endowment for International Peace - Shanghai Rule of Law Study, 2001-2007 (Box 13, Folder 73-74)
  - Carnegie Mellon University - Greening of Undergraduate Education, 2003-2007 (Box 13, Folder 75)
  - F. Y. Chang Foundation - American Studies Initiative in China (US-China Education Trust), 2010-2013 (Box 13, Folder 76-77)
  - A Christian Ministry in the National Parks - Summer Staffing, 2005-2007 (Box 13, Folder 78)
  - A Christian Ministry in the National Parks - Technological Improvements and Intern Supervision, 2001-2006 (Box 14, Folder 79)
  - Chrons, 2003 October-December (Box 14, Folder 80-84)
  - Chrons, 2003 June-September (Box 15, Folder 85-90)
  - Chrons, 2003 February-May (Box 16, Folder 91-95)
  - Chrons, September-2003 January (Box 17, Folder 96-101)
  - Chrons, 2002 June-August (Box 18, Folder 102-106)
  - Chrysler Museum of Art - Curator and Glass Collection Research (American Art Renewal Fund), 2010-2013 (Box 18, Folder 107)
  - Chrysler Museum of Art - Research, Electronic Access, and Publication of the American Paintings Collection (American Collections Enhancement (ACE) Initiative), 2000-2006 (Box 18, Folder 108)
  - Church of the Nazarene, International Board of Education - International Academy for Faculty Development, 1999-2001 (Box 19, Folder 109-110)
  - City of the University of New York - Teaching Opportunity Program, 2000-2004 (Box 19, Folder 111)
  - Cedar Rapids Museum of Art - "Grand Wood: The Five Turner Alley Studio Years, 1924-1934" Exhibition and Catalog, 2002-2006 (Box 19, Folder 112)
  - Center for Educational Innovation, Public Education Innovation - Plus Program: Preparing Luce Scholars, 2000-2003 (Box 19, Folder 113)
  - Center for Mission Research and Study at Maryknoll - Summer Program, 2002 (Box 19, Folder 114)
  - Center for Strategic and International Studies - Program for Legislators from the United States and Asia, 1998-2005 (Box 20, Folder 115)
  - Center for the Study of the Presidency - Internet Education Project on the American Presidency, 1998-2000 (Box 69, Folder 442-443)
  - Claremont McKenna University - The Yenching Experience and Higher Education in China, 1994-2010 (Box 20, Folder 116)
  - Clean Air Task Force - Investigating Non-CO2 Climate Pollution and Global Transport, 2005-2007 (Box 20, Folder 117)
  - Colgate Rochester Divinity School (Morehouse College) - Howard Thurman Papers, 1997-2000 (Box 20, Folder 118)
  - College of the Atlantic - Coastal Ecology and Integrated Marine Studies, 2002-2005 (Box 20, Folder 119)
  - Columbia University Teachers College - Education Leadership Insititute, 1999-2003 (Box 69, Folder 444)
  - Columbus Museum - Replace Computer Equipment (American Art Renewal Fund), 2011-2013 (Box 21, Folder 120)
  - Community Preparatory School - Scholarships for At-Risk Youth, 2001-2004 (Box 21, Folder 121)
  - Corning Museum of Glass - Curatorial Assistant to Survey the American Art Collection, 2012-2013 (Box 21, Folder 122)
  - CORO - Youth Leadership Initiative Program, 1998-2003 (Box 21, Folder 123)
  - Council of Independent Colleges - Leadership Program for New College Presidents, 2001-2005 (Box 21, Folder 124)
  - CrossCurrents/Association for Religion and Intellectual Life - Board and Membership of CrossCurrents, 2001-2003 (Box 21, Folder 125)
  - Dallas Museum of Art - "Gustav Stickley and the American Arts and Crafts Movement" Exhibition and Catalog, 2007-2011 (Box 22, Folder 126-127)
  - Dartmouth College - Sustainable New England Landscape, 2003-2007 (Box 22, Folder 128-130)
  - Dayton Art Institute - Research and Computerize American Art Collection (American Collections Enhancement (ACE) Initiative), 2000-2004 (Box 23, Folder 131-132)
  - Denver Art Museum - Reinterpret the Native American Collection (American Collections Enhancement (ACE) Initiative), 2000-2005 (Box 23, Folder 133)
  - Detroit Institute of Arts - "American Paintings Volume II", 1983-1999 (Box 69, Folder 445)
  - Detroit Institute of Arts - Temporary American Art Curator, 2009-2013 (Box 23, Folder 134)
  - The Door - Academic Enrichment Services for GED Students, 2001-2006 (Box 69, Folder 446)
  - The Door - Bard College Course in Humanities, 1998-1999 (Box 69, Folder 447)
  - Duke University - Continental Environmental Leadership Program, 2002-2005 (Box 24, Folder 135-137)
  - Educational Leadership Program - Academic Officers Seminars, 2003-2005 (Box 24, Folder 138)
  - Eisenhower Exchange Fellowship - Southeast Asia Single Region Program, 2002-2003 (Box 24, Folder 139-140)
  - Environmental Defense - Conserving North Caribbean Biodiversity: Marine Protective Areas and Sustainable Development in Cuba, 2002-2005 (Box 25, Folder 141)
  - Environmental Defense - Restoring Mark Twain's "Celebrated Jumping Frog of Calaveras County", 2005-2007 (Box 25, Folder 142)
  - Environmental Working Group - Persistent Pollutants in the Environment and People, 2004-2007 (Box 25, Folder 143-144)
  - The Episcopal Church Center - Fresh Start Program, 2000-2010 (Box 25, Folder 145)
  - Fauna and Flora International - Wildlife Conservation and Sustainable Development in the Cambodian Mountains, 2002-2006 (Box 25, Folder 146)
  - Federation for American Immigration Reform - Commerical Placement of Education Articles in Publications, 1999-2006 (Box 69, Folder 448)
  - Filmmakers Collaborative Inc. - "Making It" Documentary about China's Generation X, 2007-2008 (Box 26, Folder 147)
  - Fine Arts Museum of San Francisco - Reinstallation of the de Young Museum's American Art Collection, 2004-2006 (Box 26, Folder 148)
  - Franklin and Eleanor Roosevelt Institute - Renovation of the Franklin Delano Roosevelt Presidential Library, 1999-2004 (Box 70, Folder 449)
  - Franklin and Eleanor Roosevelt Institute - Restoration of Top Cottage, 1997-2003 (Box 70, Folder 450-451)
  - Garden Conservancy - Production of an Updated Film on the Preservation of Private Gardens, 2006-2007 (Box 26, Folder 149)
  - Garden Conservancy - Preserve an American Legacy: An Introduction to the Garden Conservancy, a Russell Connor Production (Box 26, Folder 149)
    Conditions Governing Access
    Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. Access copy currently unavailable. Please contact a RAC archivist for further instruction.
  - Garrison Institute - Hudson River Project: Caring for Creation and the Common Good, 2005-2007 (Box 26, Folder 150)
  - George Washington University, Elliot School of International Affairs - Faculty Position on United States-Asia Relations during the Cold War, 2000-2007 (Box 26, Folder 151)
  - Grinnell College - Four Thousand Years of Environmental Change in a Maya Forest, 2001-2005 (Box 26, Folder 152)
  - Solomon R. Guggenheim Museum - "David Smith: A Centennial" Exhibition and Catalog, 2005-2007 (Box 26, Folder 153)
  - Harvard University - China Project Fellows Exchange Program, 2001-2006 (Box 27, Folder 154)
  - Harvard University - Southeast Asian Legal Studies, 1996-2010 (Box 27, Folder 155)
  - Heritage Preservation, Inc. - Heritage Health Index, 2004-2007 (Box 27, Folder 156-158)
  - High Museum of Art - Learning Spaces for the American Art Collection, 2003-2007 (Box 28, Folder 159)
  - Higher Education Resources Services (HERS) - Summitt of Women Presidents and Chancellors in Higher Education, 2011-2013 (Box 28, Folder 160)
  - Hirshhorn Museum and Sculpture Garden - "Earth/Body: Ana Mendieta, Sculpture and Performance, 1972-1985" Exhibition and Catalog, 2002-2006 (Box 28, Folder 161-162)
  - Hirshhorn Museum and Sculpture Garden - "Isamu Noguchi" Master Sculptor" Exhibition, 2004-2006 (Box 28, Folder 163-164)
  - Hubbard Brook Research Fund - Science Links Program, 2002-2007 (Box 29, Folder 165-168)
  - Human Family Educational and Cultural Institute - Humanitas Prize, 2004-2006 (Box 29, Folder 169)
  - Independent Teaching Project - Placement of Teachers of Color into Independent Schools, 1999-2003 (Box 70, Folder 452)
  - International Arts and Artists - "Changing Identity: Recent Works by Women Artists from Vietnam" Exhibition, 2005-2007 (Box 29, Folder 170)
  - International Center of Photography - "Between the Past and Future: New Photography and Video from China" Exhibition, 2003-2005 (Box 30, Folder 171-172)
  - International Center of Photography - Online Collections Resource Project, 2006-2007 (Box 30, Folder 173)
  - International Crane Foundation - Wetland Reserve Management in China, 2002-2010 (Box 30, Folder 174-175)
  - International Foundation for Art Research - Catalogue Raisonne Database Project, 2004-2006 (Box 30, Folder 176)
  - International Student Conferences - Korea-America Student Conference, 2010-2013 (Box 31, Folder 177-178)
  - Institute of Contemporary Art (University of Pennsylvania) - "Accumulated Vision: Barry Le Va" Exhibition and Catalog, 2004-2005 (Box 31, Folder 179)
  - Japan Society - United States-Japan Exchange on Women in Public Policy, 1999-2003 (Box 31, Folder 180)
  - Japan Society - "Silver Wind: The Arts of Sakai Hoitsu (1976-1828)" Exhibition and Catalog, 2012-2013 (Box 31, Folder 181-182)
  - Jazz at Lincoln Center Inc. - 25th Anniversary Exhibition, 2012-2013 (Box 32, Folder 183)
  - Jerusalem Historical Society - Dudley Cates Research on Book of Jasher, 2000-2003 (Box 32, Folder 184)
  - Jewel Heart Center for Tibetan Buddhism and Culture - Translation of Gelek Rinpoche, 2001 (Box 32, Folder 185)
  - Johns Hopkins University (School of Advanced International Studies) - Institute for International Research and the Hopkins-Nanjing Center, 2001-2013 (Box 32, Folder 186-187)
  - Johns Hopkins University (School of Advanced International Studies) - Joint MA Program at the Hopkins-Nanjing Center, 2006-2013 (Box 32, Folder 188)
  - Johns Hopkins University (School of Advanced International Studies) - Southeast Asian Studies (Renewal), 1994-2002 (Box 32, Folder 189)
  - Herbert F. Johnson Museum of Art - "Byrdcliffe: An American Arts and Crafts Colony" Exhibition and Catalog, 2000-2005 (Box 33, Folder 190-191)
  - The Kindling Group - "The Calling" Documentary Outreach and Education Campaign, 2006-2008 (Box 33, Folder 192)
  - Kips Bay Boys and Girls Club - College Bound Program, 2000-2002 (Box 33, Folder 193)
  - Korea Society - Christianity in Korea, 1996-1997 (Box 33, Folder 194)
  - Korea Society - Transmitting the Forms of Divinity: Early Buddhist Art from Korea and Japan, 2001-2003 (Box 33, Folder 195)
  - LaGuardia Community College - Office of Transfer Services, 2011-2013 (Box 33, Folder 196)
  - The Land Institute - Natural Systems Agriculture, 2004-2007 (Box 34, Folder 197)
  - Lehigh University - Bridging Disciplines and Cultures, 2009-2013 (Box 34, Folder 198-199)
  - Lehigh University - Chinese Bridge Project, 2011-2013 (Box 34, Folder 200-201)
  - Lexington Theological Seminary - Longitudinal Study of Students, 2001-2002 (Box 34, Folder 202)
  - Libraries for the Future - Youth Access Program in Harlem, 2000-2002 (Box 35, Folder 203)
  - Library of Congress - Asian Collections Fellowship and Aquisition Program, 2000-2013 (Box 35, Folder 204-205)
  - Library of Congress (Congressional Research Service) - Orientation Seminar for 110th Congress, 2006-2007 (Box 35, Folder 206-207)
  - Library of Congress (Congressional Research Service) - Orientation Seminar for 109th Congress, 2004-2005 (Box 35, Folder 208)
  - Lincoln Center for the Performing Arts - The Peony Pavilion, 1999-2001 (Box 36, Folder 209)
  - Long Bow Group - Multimedia Encyclopedia of Twentieth-Century China, 1999-2005 (Box 36, Folder 210)
  - Long Island University - Center for Urban Educators, 1999-2006 (Box 36, Folder 211)
  - Long Island University - Friends World Program, 1995-1999 (Box 36, Folder 212)
  - Long Island University - Restoration of Ilya Bolotwsky Mural, 2001 (Box 36, Folder 213)
  - Los Angeles County Museum of Art - American Art Collections Online, 2002-2005 (Box 37, Folder 214-215)
  - Madison Avenue Presbyterian Church - Capital Campaign Project, 1998-2000 (Box 37, Folder 216)
  - Madison Square Park Conservancy - Art Curator, 2012 (Box 37, Folder 217)
  - Madison Square Park Conservancy - Art Program, 2010-2013 (Box 37, Folder 218)
  - Maier Museum of Art (Randolph Macon Woman's College) - Computerization of American Arts Collection (American Collections Enhancement (ACE) Initiative), 2000-2005 (Box 37, Folder 219-220)
  - Mansfield Center for Pacific Affairs - Rule of Law and Acceptance in Asia, 1999-2001 (Box 37, Folder 221)
  - Marylhurst College - Doctor of Ministry Program, 1998-2001 (Box 38, Folder 222)
  - Center for Mission Research and Study at Maryknoll - Grassroots Responses of Christian Communities in Situations of Violent Conflict, 1999-2003 (Box 38, Folder 223)
  - Massachusetts Institute of Technology - Lucian Pye Fellowship in Comparative Politics, 1993-2000 (Box 38, Folder 224)
  - Massachusetts Institute of Technology - Visualizing Cultures Project, 2010-2013 (Box 38, Folder 225-226)
  - Math/Science Network - Expanding your Horizons Conferences, 2004-2006 (Box 38, Folder 227)
  - MEM Associates, Inc. - Arts and Religion in American Life, 1999-2001 (Box 38, Folder 228)
  - Metropolitan Museum of Art - American Sculpture Catalog, 1982-2001 (Box 70, Folder 453)
  - Metropolitan Museum of Art - Colonial Silver Collection, 1983-1987 (Box 70, Folder 454)
  - Metropolitan Museum of Art - Gilbert Stuart, 2001-2005 (Box 39, Folder 229-230)
  - Mill Neck Manor School for the Deaf - Deaf Ministry Pilot Program, 2000-2002 (Box 39, Folder 231)
  - Minneapolis Institute of Arts - "Beauford Delany: From New York to Paris" Exhibition and Catalog, 2002-2005 (Box 39, Folder 232)
  - Minneapolis Institute of Arts - Prairie School Purcell-Cutts House (American Art Renewal Fund), 2011-2013 (Box 39, Folder 233)
  - Minnesota Public Radio/American Public Media - Speaking of Faith Radio Program, 2005-2013 (Box 40, Folder 234)
  - Minnesota Public Radio/American Public Media - Speaking of Faith: Recovering Chinese Religiosities (with Mayfair Yang), 2008 (Box 40, Folder 234)
  - Minnesota Public Radio/American Public Media - Speaking of Faith: The Ethics of Aid: One Kenyan's Perspective (with Binyavanga Wainaina), 2008 (Box 40, Folder 234)
  - Minnesota Public Radio/American Public Media - Speaking of Faith: No More Taking Sides, 2008 (Box 40, Folder 234)
  - Minnesota Public Radio/American Public Media - Speaking of Faith: The Ecstatic Faith of Rumi, 2007-2007 (Box 40, Folder 234)
  - Minnesota Public Radio/American Public Media - Speaking of Faith Radio Program (Renewals), 2008-2013 (Box 40, Folder 235-236)
  - Modern Art Museum of Fort Worth - "110 Modern Art Museum of Fort Worth" Exhibition and Catalog, 2001-2003 (Box 40, Folder 237)
  - Mongolian-American Cultural Association - Festival of Mongolian Programs, 2000-2001 (Box 40, Folder 238)
  - Montclair Art Museum - Morgan Russell Archives Project, 2003-2006 (Box 40, Folder 239-240)
  - Monterey Institute of International Studies - Chinese/English Interpreter, 1991-2000 (Box 41, Folder 241)
  - Morgan Library - Al Hirschfeld Exhibition, 2001-2002 (Box 41, Folder 242)
  - Mount Baker Theatre - Renovation of Education Space, 2000 (Box 41, Folder 243)
  - Mount St. Mary's College - Center for Urban Partnership's Education Partnership, 1998-2002 (Box 41, Folder 244-245)
  - The Mountain Institute - Peak Enterprise Program, 1999-2006 (Box 41, Folder 246)
  - Muse Film and Television - "Contested Ground: American Art in the 20th Century" Documentary, 2000-2005 (Box 42, Folder 247-248)
  - Museum of Arts and Design - "Crafting Modernism: Midcentury American Art and Design" Exhibition and Catalog, 2004-2013 (Box 42, Folder 249-250)
    Scope and Contents
    Previously called "Centenary IV: The Studio Craft Movement 1945-1969: A Community Emerges"
  - Museum of Arts and Design - Curatorial Assistant (American Art Renewal Fund), 2011-2013 (Box 42, Folder 251)
  - Museum of Biblical Art - "Louis C. Tiffany and the Art of Devotion" Exhibition and Catalog, 2011-2013 (Box 42, Folder 252)
  - Museum of Fine Arts, Boston - American Paintings Summary Catalog, 1987-1998 (Box 70, Folder 455)